const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A young lady presents with irregular vaginal bleeding. She is concerned for her health because her mother had cervical carcinoma. The gynecologist advises a pap smear testing which reveals cervical intraepithelial neoplasia. Cervical intraepithelial neoplasia is strongly associated with which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Ureaplasma urealyticum","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex virus","bool":false},{"option":"Human papilloma virus","bool":true},{"option":"Cytomegalovirus","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"An 18-year-old girl is diagnosed with Turner's syndrome. What is the most probable chromosomal makeup in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"46, XXX","bool":false},{"option":"46, XXY","bool":false},{"option":"46, XY","bool":false},{"option":"45, XO","bool":true},{"option":"46, XX","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 19-year-old female patient comes to the outpatient department (OPD) with the complaint of primary amenorrhea. She has well-developed breasts and pubic hair, but the uterus and vagina are absent. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Gonadal dysgenesis","bool":false},{"option":"Klinefelters syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Mullerian agenesis","bool":true},{"option":"XXY syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Turner's syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 16-year-old boy was seen by a surgeon with complaints of swelling and tenderness in his left testes. This condition is most likely be produced by thrombosis in which of the following veins?","answers":[{"option":"Left internal pudendal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Left external pudendal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Left inferior epigastric vein","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Left renal vein","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 19-year-old black, female patient is in her 32nd week of gestation and is admitted to the labor and delivery with a blood pressure of 165/110 mmHg and proteinuria in triage. During her pregnancy, she has suffered from agitation, behavioral changes, and edema. Which of the following best describes her pathogenesis?","answers":[{"option":"Proliferation of extravillous trophoblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Early pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Increase estrogenic metabolism","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased synthesis of amniotic fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Abnormal placental vasculature and coagulation abnormalities","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 22-year-old obese, married nulliparous woman visits a gynecologist for irregular menstrual cycles for the past 1 year. On examination, it was found that she has hirsutism, alopecia, and acanthosis nigricans. Her ultrasound shows multiple fluid-filled sacs in the ovary. What does this indicate?","answers":[{"option":"Primary infertility","bool":false},{"option":"Endometrioses","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine fibroid","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic ovarian syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 26-year-old married lady comes to the clinic with the complaint of multiple miscarriages. Further inquiry reveals that all her pregnancy losses occurred at 10-12th weeks of gestation. Which of the following best describes the condition?","answers":[{"option":"Placental site trophoblastic tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Ectopic tubal pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Complete hydatidiform mole","bool":false},{"option":"Ectopic abdominal pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Spontaneous abortion","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 3-month-old male infant is brought to the outpatient department (OPD) for a routine check-up. On thorough examination, it is found that he has cryptorchidism. Which of the following best describes the condition?","answers":[{"option":"Accumulation of fluid in the testes","bool":false},{"option":"Agenesis of testes","bool":false},{"option":"Two testes in each scrotum","bool":false},{"option":"Enlarged testes in the scrotum","bool":false},{"option":"Testes fail to descend into the scrotum","bool":true}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 3-year-old male infant is brought to the clinic after his mother notices urine being expelled from the dorsal aspect of the penis. Abnormality in which of the following embryological structures results in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Urethral folds","bool":false},{"option":"Urogenital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Spongy urethra","bool":false},{"option":"Phallus","bool":true},{"option":"Labioscrotal folds","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 30-year-old male comes to the emergency department with complaints of fever for 2 days, with nocturia, intermittent stream, and pain during micturition. On palpation, the prostate feels boggy, rubbery, and tender to touch. Which of the following is the most probable cause of the condition?","answers":[{"option":"Prostatic carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Nodular enlargement of prostate","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic prostatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute prostatitis","bool":true},{"option":"Benign prostatic hyperplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 34-year-old lady comes to the clinic with the complaint of abnormal menstrual bleeding. She reports bleeding for 9 days but the bleeding is regular, occurring after every 28 days. Which of the following best describes the bleeding pattern seen here?","answers":[{"option":"Metrorrhagia","bool":false},{"option":"Intermenstrual bleeding","bool":false},{"option":"Polymenorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Menorrhagia","bool":true},{"option":"Menometrorrhagia","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 40-year-old man has developed an infection of the testes. Which of the following lymph nodes is most likely to be enlarged?","answers":[{"option":"Femoral lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Deep inguinal lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial inguinal lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Para-aortic lymph nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Aortic lymph nodes","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 45-year-old lady presents with heavy uterine bleeding. She reports irregular menstrual cycles for the past year. She is married but has no children and is clinically obese. An endometrial biopsy shows an increased gland to stroma ratio and the glands are cystically dilated. No nuclear atypia is seen. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Senile cystic atrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Atypical endometrial hyperplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Endometrial carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Non atypical endometrial hyperplasia","bool":true},{"option":"Ectopic pregnancy","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 46-year-old female presents with a history of infection in her perineal region. On comprehensive examination, it was found that the superior boundary of superficial perineal space is torn. Which structure is most likely to be injured?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial perineal fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Colle's fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Deep perineal fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Perineal membrane","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 55-year-old female presents with a 3-month history of postmenopausal bleeding. She was previously diagnosed with endometrial hyperplasia on biopsy but she never returned for a follow-up and never received the treatment. Which of the following is the most probable cause of abnormal uterine bleeding?","answers":[{"option":"Senile cystic atrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Ectopic pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Endometrial carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Oral contraceptives","bool":false},{"option":"Endometriosis","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 62-year-old patient comes with a complaint of urgency, frequency, nocturia, and post-void dribbling. He is most probably suffering from prostatic enlargement. Which route of examination should be used to examine the prostate gland?","answers":[{"option":"Perineum examination","bool":false},{"option":"Abdominal examination","bool":false},{"option":"Cystourethroscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Digital rectal examination","bool":true},{"option":"Supra pubic palpation","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 65-year-old male patient is admitted to the ward with lower urinary tract symptoms. He gets diagnosed with prostatic cancer. Which of the following is not consistent with prostatic carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Multi-nodularity","bool":false},{"option":"Hard in consistency","bool":false},{"option":"Regular and smooth surface","bool":true},{"option":"Prostatic enlargement","bool":false},{"option":"Obscured median sulcus","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 31-year-old female comes with a history of vaginal discharge. The discharge is green in color and is foul-smelling. On lab investigation, it is found to be due to pelvic inflammatory disease. Which of the following is related to this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Improper mitosis","bool":false},{"option":"Abnormal fertilization","bool":false},{"option":"Abnormal ovulation","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammation of uterus","bool":true},{"option":"Improper implantation","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A female patient came to the gynecology outpatient department (OPD) with a complaint of infertility. After lab investigation, it was found that the problem is with the conduction of sperms and ovum to the site of fertilization. What is the site of fertilization?","answers":[{"option":"Ovaries","bool":false},{"option":"Uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Vagina","bool":false},{"option":"Fallopian tubes","bool":true},{"option":"Cervix","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is a common intermediate in the estrogen synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Cortisol","bool":false},{"option":"Aldosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Corticosterone","bool":false},{"option":"11-deoxycorticosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Androstenedione","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 65-year-old male patient complains of urgency and frequency, especially at night. His urologist suspects benign prostate hyperplasia and places him on 5-alpha-reductase inhibitor therapy. What does this enzyme promote?","answers":[{"option":"Conversion of cAMP to adenosine","bool":false},{"option":"Release of calcium from endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Conversion of angiotensin I to angiotensin II","bool":false},{"option":"Prostaglandin synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Conversion of testosterone to dihydrotestosterone (DHT)","bool":true}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which one of the following represents the female pelvis with a greater transverse diameter of the outlet than the anteroposterior diameter?","answers":[{"option":"Gynecoid pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Mesatipellic pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Dolicocephalic pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Android pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Platypelloid pelvis","bool":true}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A histopathologist observes simple columnar cells with simple tubular glands embedded in a thick stroma while examining a slide. Which of the following is represented by the slide?","answers":[{"option":"Epididymis","bool":false},{"option":"Uterus","bool":true},{"option":"Prostate gland","bool":false},{"option":"Fallopian tubes","bool":false},{"option":"Ovaries","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A mother is worried about her 17-year-old daughter who has not menstruated yet. She has well-developed secondary sexual characteristics. Ultrasound shows normal ovaries, but the uterus is absent. Which of the following is the most accurate condition describing her state?","answers":[{"option":"Rokitansky syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Sheehan's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Turner's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Klinefelter's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Testicular feminization syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A mother of two children comes to a family planning clinic for long-term contraception. What would be the most suitable method for her?","answers":[{"option":"Intrauterine contraceptive devices (IUCD)","bool":true},{"option":"Injectable contraceptives","bool":false},{"option":"Oral contraceptives","bool":false},{"option":"Condoms","bool":false},{"option":"Natural method","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 31-year-old female patient presents with a history of recurrent abortions. After a thorough investigation, it is found that the problem is with implantation. What is the most common site of implantation?","answers":[{"option":"Ovary","bool":false},{"option":"Vagina","bool":false},{"option":"Fallopian tubes","bool":false},{"option":"Uterus","bool":true},{"option":"Cervix","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"The addition of progestins for 10-12 days each month in an estrogen replacement therapy in menopausal women is recommended. What is the purpose of this?","answers":[{"option":"Enhances metabolic effects of estrogen therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Reduces the risk of endometrial carcinoma due to estrogen","bool":true},{"option":"Reverses vulvar atrophy occurring in post menopausal women","bool":false},{"option":"Reduces the risk of myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Enhances pharmacological properties of the estrogen","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"After a rotation in the psychiatric ward, the teacher asks about the reproductive health problems of women in Pakistan. Which option best describes good reproductive healthcare practice?","answers":[{"option":"Teenage sex and postnatal care","bool":false},{"option":"Healthy sexuality, age related factors and intended births","bool":false},{"option":"Social stigma, unsafe pregnancy and sexually transmitted diseases","bool":false},{"option":"Healthy sexuality, safe pregnancy and childbearing and intended births","bool":true},{"option":"Antenatal care, post natal care and child marriages","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 25-year-old girl presents to the emergency room after noticing an abdominal mass. She has pain in her hypogastric region and her menstrual cycle is irregular. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pelvic inflammatory disease","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroids","bool":false},{"option":"Mesenteric cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Ovarian cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Endometriosis","bool":true}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is a part of the broad ligament?","answers":[{"option":"Uterosacral ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Ligamentum teres","bool":false},{"option":"Cardinal ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Ovarian ligament","bool":true},{"option":"Suspensory ligament of ovary","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which process is affected by the blockage of the isthmus of the uterine tube?","answers":[{"option":"Meiosis II","bool":false},{"option":"Meiosis I","bool":false},{"option":"Ovulation","bool":false},{"option":"Metaphase II","bool":true},{"option":"Prophase I","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Increasing the intake of which of the following should be done in women who are trying to conceive?","answers":[{"option":"Potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Nickel","bool":false},{"option":"Folic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Iron","bool":false},{"option":"Lycopene","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 45-year-old, para 3+0 female complains of heavy menstrual bleeding for the past year. She is taking prescribed medication but has seen no improvement. What will be the next step?","answers":[{"option":"Coagulation profile","bool":false},{"option":"Hysterectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Endometrial sampling","bool":true},{"option":"Vaginal swab for culture & sensitivity (C/S)","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following does not form the boundary of a urogenital triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Urogenital diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Pubic symphysis","bool":false},{"option":"Ischio-pubic ramus","bool":false},{"option":"Ischial tuberosities","bool":false},{"option":"Ischial spines","bool":true}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Congenital anomalies can lead to the absence of certain organs. In incomplete Mullerian duct aplasia, which of the following would be present?","answers":[{"option":"Ovaries","bool":true},{"option":"Cervix","bool":false},{"option":"Vagina","bool":false},{"option":"Fallopian tube","bool":false},{"option":"Uterus","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"During a hysterectomy, the surgeon notices severe bleeding from the artery that remains within a true pelvis. Which one of these is most likely be the injured artery?","answers":[{"option":"Internal pudendal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine artery","bool":true},{"option":"Obturator artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior gluteal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Iliolumbar artery","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"What is the primary source of progesterone in late pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Corpus luteum","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenal cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Placenta","bool":true},{"option":"Ovaries","bool":false},{"option":"Graafian follicles","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"During model studies, the students were discussing the boundaries of the ischiorectal fossa. One student pointed out the structure forming its medial wall. Which structure forms the medial wall of the ischiorectal fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Levator ani","bool":false},{"option":"External anal sphincter","bool":true},{"option":"Obturator fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Urogenital diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator internus muscle","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is an intermediate in progesterone synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Estradiol","bool":false},{"option":"Androstenedione","bool":false},{"option":"Deoxycorticosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxyprogestrone","bool":false},{"option":"Pregnenolone","bool":true}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which one of the following best describes the components of reproductive health?","answers":[{"option":"Health of youth, contraception, abortion, and sexually transmitted diseases","bool":false},{"option":"Maternal health, child health and diseases of females","bool":false},{"option":"Maternal health, abortion, and contraception","bool":true},{"option":"General health of public, abortion and contraception","bool":false},{"option":"Public health, maternal health and contraception","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"The external urethral sphincter is a part of which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Pelvic diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial perineal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Urogenital diaphragm","bool":true},{"option":"Bulbospongiosus muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Levator ani muscle","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which one of the following is the primary function of follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)?","answers":[{"option":"Involution of corpus luteum","bool":false},{"option":"Spermatogenesis","bool":true},{"option":"Testosterone production","bool":false},{"option":"Conversion of cholesterol to pregnenolone","bool":false},{"option":"Ovulation","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which one of the following is not a part of uterine tubes or fallopian tubes?","answers":[{"option":"Cervix","bool":true},{"option":"Infundibulum","bool":false},{"option":"Fimbriae","bool":false},{"option":"Isthmus","bool":false},{"option":"Ampulla","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"The proliferation of the corpus luteum is promoted by prolactin which stimulates the production of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Somatomedin","bool":false},{"option":"Thyrotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroxine","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":true},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is associated with increased estrogen levels in the body?","answers":[{"option":"Sheehan syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Amenorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Klinefelter syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Gynecomastia","bool":true},{"option":"Hypofunctional ovaries","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is not the side effect of estrogen in postmenopausal hormone replacement therapy?","answers":[{"option":"Blood clotting","bool":false},{"option":"Breast pain","bool":false},{"option":"Hot flashes","bool":true},{"option":"Uterine cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Vaginal discharge","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is the broad ligament that covers the uterine tube?","answers":[{"option":"Ovarian ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Mesovarium","bool":false},{"option":"Ligament of ovary","bool":false},{"option":"Mesosalpinx","bool":true},{"option":"Mesometrium","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of these immunoglobulins can cross the placental barrier?","answers":[{"option":"IgE","bool":false},{"option":"IgG","bool":true},{"option":"IgM","bool":false},{"option":"IgD","bool":false},{"option":"IgA","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"The secretion of inhibin is caused by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Reticulocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cells","bool":false},{"option":"Leydig cells","bool":false},{"option":"Sertoli cells","bool":true}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which type of cells are present in breast milk?","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophils and macrophages","bool":true},{"option":"Mast cells and plasma cells","bool":false},{"option":"Red blood cells and reticulocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Red blood cells and plasma cells","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cells and reticulocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 15-year-old girl comes to the outpatient department with complaints of cyclical lower abdominal pain. On examination, she has suprapubic swelling and a bluish bulge is seen in the vestibule. What is the most probable cause?","answers":[{"option":"Turner syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Mullerian agenesis","bool":false},{"option":"XY gonadal genesis","bool":false},{"option":"Imperforate hymen","bool":true},{"option":"Congenital adrenal hyperplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which is the main ligament of support for the uterus?","answers":[{"option":"Mesometrium","bool":false},{"option":"Broad ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Round ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Cardinal ligament","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which is the most common site of implantation of the fetus in an ectopic pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Cervix","bool":false},{"option":"Infundibulum","bool":false},{"option":"Isthmus","bool":false},{"option":"Uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Ampulla","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Combined oral contraceptive pills contain which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Antiprogestin","bool":false},{"option":"Selective estrogen receptor modulators (SERM)","bool":false},{"option":"Androgen","bool":false},{"option":"Antiandrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Progestin","bool":true}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 25-year-old woman, mother of two children, wants to completely avoid further pregnancies. Which type of contraceptives should be suggested to her?","answers":[{"option":"Intrauterine device (IUD)","bool":false},{"option":"Coitus","bool":false},{"option":"Tubal ligation","bool":true},{"option":"Combined oral contraceptive","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen supplement","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"How do oral contraceptives prevent pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Prevent ovulation","bool":true},{"option":"Prevent menstruation","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibit fertilization","bool":false},{"option":"Reduce egg population","bool":false},{"option":"Prevent implantation","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Hemoglobin and hematocrit levels are at their lowest levels at which stage of pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Fifth month","bool":false},{"option":"Second month","bool":false},{"option":"Ninth month","bool":false},{"option":"Seventh month","bool":true},{"option":"First trimester","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following conditions may occur during pregnancy due to iodine deficiency in the expectant mother?","answers":[{"option":"Hypothyroidism","bool":true},{"option":"Calciuria","bool":false},{"option":"Hypokalemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperthyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatemia","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which structure is present inferior to the prostate?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Spongy urethra","bool":false},{"option":"Prostatic urticle","bool":false},{"option":"Seminal vesicle","bool":false},{"option":"Cowper's glands","bool":true}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"What is the normal position of a nulliparous uterus?","answers":[{"option":"Anteflexed and retroverted","bool":false},{"option":"Retroflexed only","bool":false},{"option":"Anteflexed only","bool":false},{"option":"Retroverted and retroflexed","bool":false},{"option":"Anteflexed and anteverted","bool":true}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"The predominant form of estrogen in a non-pregnant female is which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Estradiol","bool":true},{"option":"Estriol","bool":false},{"option":"Androstenedione","bool":false},{"option":"Estrone","bool":false},{"option":"Ethynyl estradiol","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"What is the WHO recommended duration for exclusive breastfeeding?","answers":[{"option":"1 year","bool":false},{"option":"2 years","bool":false},{"option":"6 months","bool":true},{"option":"4 months","bool":false},{"option":"3 months","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which surface of the bladder is not in contact with the levator ani?","answers":[{"option":"Superior","bool":true},{"option":"Medial","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral","bool":false},{"option":"Mediolateral","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Higher than normal levels of progesterone are found in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Ectopic pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital adrenal hyperplasia","bool":true},{"option":"Fetal death","bool":false},{"option":"Amenorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Anovulatory cycle","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Highly coiled spiral arteries and edema in the endometrium are characteristic of which of the following stages of menstruation?","answers":[{"option":"Early proliferative stage","bool":false},{"option":"Menstrual phase","bool":false},{"option":"Early secretory stage","bool":false},{"option":"Late secretory stage","bool":true},{"option":"Late proliferative stage","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 30-year-old female patient is being evaluated for infertility. Serum gonadotropins, estradiol, progesterone, and prolactin levels are measured in a test that is advised to obtain data by a blood sample on her 21st day of menstruation cycle. Which of the following will indicate if the cycle has been ovulatory or not?","answers":[{"option":"Progesterone","bool":true},{"option":"Leutinizing hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Estradiol","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Follicle stimulating hormone","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following structures is present in the deep perineal pouch of a female?","answers":[{"option":"Sphincter urethrae","bool":true},{"option":"Greater vestibular glands","bool":false},{"option":"Clitoris","bool":false},{"option":"Bulbs of the vestibule","bool":false},{"option":"Bulbourethral glands","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"In granulosa cells of follicles, testosterone is converted to beta-estradiol. Which of the following enzymes is important for this conversion?","answers":[{"option":"Dehydratase","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygenase","bool":false},{"option":"Isomerase","bool":false},{"option":"Reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Aromatase","bool":true}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following structures is present in superficial perineal pouch of the males?","answers":[{"option":"Ischiocavernous muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Seminal vesicles","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous urethra","bool":false},{"option":"Neck of bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which one of the following options correctly defines infertility?","answers":[{"option":"Failure to conceive after six months of unprotected intercourse","bool":false},{"option":"Failure to conceive  after one year of unprotected intercourse","bool":true},{"option":"Failure to conceive after three years of unprotected intercourse","bool":false},{"option":"Failure to conceive after five years of unprotected intercourse","bool":false},{"option":"Failure to conceive after four years of unprotected intercourse","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which hormone makes the mucus of the cervix receptive to the sperm passage?","answers":[{"option":"Estrogen","bool":true},{"option":"Growth hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"The levator prostate in males is a part of which of these structures?","answers":[{"option":"Obturator internus","bool":false},{"option":"Levator pelpebrae superioris","bool":false},{"option":"Levator ani","bool":true},{"option":"Pelvic diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Piriformis","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Mrs. X is an influential social worker with experience of working with various government and non-government organizations. She now wants to take an initiative to empower the transgender community. She wants to make them realize that they should not be dependent on charity throughout their life and have to self-support themselves. This can lead to social, psychological, or even mental health problems in them. Which of the following would be the best way to bring the change without causing much damage?","answers":[{"option":"By creating a public awareness about the rights of transgenders","bool":false},{"option":"Young people should assist marginalized population because they better understand their needs","bool":false},{"option":"By helping them create their own welfare organization and giving them charge because they better understand their own needs","bool":true},{"option":"By creating a charitable organization so that they do not feel themselves to be powerless","bool":false},{"option":"By helping them make decisions","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of these follicles is seen in the prepubertal stage?","answers":[{"option":"Primordial follicle","bool":true},{"option":"Growing/preantral follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Primary follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Atretic follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary follicle","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"There are two photomicrographs of the ovary shown to a medical student, prepubertal and pubertal stage. How can these two be differentiated?","answers":[{"option":"No atretic follicles are seen in pubertal stage","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":true},{"option":"Covered by stratified squamous epithelium and stratum granulosum at pubertal stage","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary follicles are seen in prepubertal stage","bool":false},{"option":"Primary follicles seen in prepubertal stage","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of these layers sloughs off during the menstrual period?","answers":[{"option":"Endometrium","bool":true},{"option":"Perimetrium","bool":false},{"option":"Myometrium","bool":false},{"option":"Rugae","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical mucosa","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"What is the major form of estrogen produced from menarche till menopause?","answers":[{"option":"Estriol","bool":false},{"option":"Estrone","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-estradiol","bool":true},{"option":"Esterol","bool":false},{"option":"Androstenedione","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Prevention of ovulation by inhibiting gonadotropin release from the pituitary is the mechanism of action of which of the following contraceptive method?","answers":[{"option":"Intrauterine contraceptive devices","bool":false},{"option":"Rhythm method","bool":false},{"option":"Sterilization","bool":false},{"option":"Contraceptive diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Combined oral pills","bool":true}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which one of the following releases prolactin inhibiting hormone?","answers":[{"option":"Pancreas","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior pituitary gland","bool":false},{"option":"Ovaries","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior pituitary gland","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following contains pseudostratified columnar epithelium along with corpora amylacea?","answers":[{"option":"Ejaculatory duct","bool":false},{"option":"Seminiferous tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate gland","bool":true},{"option":"Epididymis","bool":false},{"option":"Ductus deferens","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following parameter is not included in normal semen analysis according to the World Health Organization?","answers":[{"option":"Semen pH","bool":false},{"option":"Semen color","bool":true},{"option":"Sperm morphology","bool":false},{"option":"Sperm count","bool":false},{"option":"Sperm motility","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is primarily a prolactin inhibiting factor?","answers":[{"option":"Dopamine","bool":true},{"option":"Somatotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Metoclopramide","bool":false},{"option":"Vasopressin","bool":false},{"option":"Haloperidol","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following types of epithelia lines the rete testis?","answers":[{"option":"Simple squamous epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Simple columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified columnar ciliated epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Simple cuboidal epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"Simple columnar ciliated epthelium","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"An anal fissure is a tear in the thin moist mucosa that lines the anus and is a very painful condition. Which of the following nerves innervates this area?","answers":[{"option":"Superior hypogastric plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Ilioinguinal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior rectal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior hypogastric plexus","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Testosterone is produced by the Leydig cells of the testes. Which of the following stimulates its secretion?","answers":[{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen and follicle-stimulating hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone","bool":true},{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Tearing of the pelvic diaphragm during childbirth can lead to the paralysis of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Obturator internus","bool":false},{"option":"Sphincter ani externus","bool":false},{"option":"Levator ani","bool":true},{"option":"Sphincter urethrae","bool":false},{"option":"Piriformis","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following indicates the concentration of progesterone during the luteal phase of a menstrual cycle?","answers":[{"option":"6.0-30 ng/mL","bool":true},{"option":"750 ng/mL","bool":false},{"option":"0.2-203 ng/mL","bool":false},{"option":"900 ng/mL","bool":false},{"option":"3.0-5.0 ng/mL","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following drugs when administered orally causes cervical ripening in a pregnant woman to help induce labor?","answers":[{"option":"Raloxifene","bool":false},{"option":"Mifepristone","bool":true},{"option":"Temoxifen","bool":false},{"option":"Levonorgestrel","bool":false},{"option":"Natural progesterone","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following conditions can cause retrograde ejaculation?","answers":[{"option":"Injury to external urethral sphincter","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary reflux disease","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary infection","bool":false},{"option":"Enlarged prostate","bool":false},{"option":"Injury to internal urethral sphincter","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is an intermediate in the biogenic synthesis of adrenocortical hormones?","answers":[{"option":"Androstenedione","bool":false},{"option":"Estrone","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":true},{"option":"Estradiol","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following structures is supplied by the inferior vesical artery?","answers":[{"option":"Ureters","bool":false},{"option":"Superior surface of bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Seminal vesicles","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior surface of bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Posteroinferior part of bladder in females","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"The health status of any individual depends on how empowered they feel at any point in time. You are assessing the perceived self-image of individuals in the community. While interviewing a poor lady, she replies that she works as a housekeeper and the employer pays a very small amount because she belongs to a minority group. Which of the following describes this condition accurately?","answers":[{"option":"Self perception","bool":false},{"option":"Critical self-awareness","bool":true},{"option":"Participatory competence","bool":false},{"option":"Sustaining participation","bool":false},{"option":"Citizen participation","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"The greater vestibular glands open into which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Vestibule on each side of vaginal orifice","bool":true},{"option":"Glans clitoris","bool":false},{"option":"Bulbourethral ducts","bool":false},{"option":"Bulbs of the vestibule","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"What is the free anterosuperior margin of the broad ligament of the uterus called?","answers":[{"option":"Broad ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Cardinal ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Mesosalpinx","bool":true},{"option":"Ovarian ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Round ligament","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is the first hormone secreted by the placenta?","answers":[{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":true},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Pregnenolone","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"The descent of testes involves various hormonal and mechanical factors. Which of the following does not help in the descent of testes?","answers":[{"option":"Estrogen","bool":true},{"option":"Intra-abdominal pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin like growth factor 3","bool":false},{"option":"Processus vaginalis","bool":false},{"option":"Gubernaculum tension","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"How many days does it take for the process of spermatogenesis to complete?","answers":[{"option":"21","bool":false},{"option":"120","bool":false},{"option":"100","bool":false},{"option":"74","bool":true},{"option":"50","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"The early growth of the primary follicle in an ovary till the antral stage is stimulated by which of the following hormones?","answers":[{"option":"Progesterone and estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone","bool":true}]},{"id":98,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is the most active androgen?","answers":[{"option":"Androsterone","bool":false},{"option":"Androstenedione","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Dehydroepiandrosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Dihydrotestosterone","bool":true}]},{"id":99,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"The testes secrete various male sex hormones, collectively called androgens. Which of the following cells secretes testosterone?","answers":[{"option":"Sertoli cells","bool":false},{"option":"Leydig cells","bool":true},{"option":"Spermatogonium","bool":false},{"option":"Desmosomes","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymal cell","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"The prostate is a branched tubuloalveolar gland that is divided into multiple zones. Which of the following zones make(s) up the majority of the gland?","answers":[{"option":"Peripheral","bool":false},{"option":"Central","bool":false},{"option":"Central and peripheral","bool":true},{"option":"Central and transitional","bool":false},{"option":"Transitional","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which one of the following is the principal and the most active form of the estrogenic hormone in circulation?","answers":[{"option":"Methoxy-esterone","bool":false},{"option":"Estrone","bool":false},{"option":"Epiestriol","bool":false},{"option":"β-estradiol","bool":true},{"option":"Estriol","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is the precursor in testosterone production?","answers":[{"option":"Cholesterol","bool":true},{"option":"Thymine","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false},{"option":"Arachidonic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Bile","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"The parasympathetic preganglionic fibers in pelvic splanchnic nerve synapse with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ganglia in or near the visceral wall or pelvic plexus","bool":true},{"option":"Ganglion impar","bool":false},{"option":"Collateral ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal root ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic chain ganglia","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"What is the most common site of an ectopic tubal pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Ampulla","bool":true},{"option":"Abdominal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Infundibulum","bool":false},{"option":"Cervix","bool":false},{"option":"Isthmus","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is the major trophic hormone for the Sertoli cells?","answers":[{"option":"Luteinizing hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibin","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"The lumen of the seminal vesicle is highly irregular, with a honeycomb appearance. Which of the following types of epithelia is present in the seminal vesicle?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudostratified columnar epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"Simple squamous epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Transitional epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified cuboidal epithelium","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following contains the ischiocavernosus muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial perineal space","bool":true},{"option":"Ischio-rectal fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Deep perineal space","bool":false},{"option":"True pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Around the bulb of the penis","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following represents the intratesticular ducts in males?","answers":[{"option":"Efferent ductules, rete testis, and ductus deferens","bool":false},{"option":"Epididymis and ductus deferens","bool":false},{"option":"Efferent ductules and ductus deferens","bool":false},{"option":"Tubuli recti and rete testis","bool":true},{"option":"Efferent ductules, rete testis, and tubuli recti","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following structures is most likely to be damaged by a stab wound in the ischiorectal fossa about 2 centimeters lateral to the anal canal?","answers":[{"option":"Perineal body","bool":false},{"option":"Crus of the penis","bool":false},{"option":"Pudendal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Vesicular bulb","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior rectal artery","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following shapes is the normal female type, characterized by a typically rounded oval pelvic inlet?","answers":[{"option":"Android","bool":false},{"option":"Gynecoid","bool":true},{"option":"Anthropoid","bool":false},{"option":"Arthroid","bool":false},{"option":"Platypelloid","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the vaginal mucosa?","answers":[{"option":"Its cells secrete lactic acid","bool":false},{"option":"It is lubricated by the glands located in the cervix","bool":true},{"option":"It is lined by stratified columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"It does not possess elastic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"It is lined by stratified squamous keratinized epithelium","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following adverse effects is not associated with the use of oral contraceptives?","answers":[{"option":"Nausea","bool":false},{"option":"Breast tenderness","bool":false},{"option":"Increased risk of ovarian cancer","bool":true},{"option":"Increased risk of migraines","bool":false},{"option":"Edema","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which impairment of the male reproductive system will not lead to sterility?","answers":[{"option":"Prostatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Blockage of the vas deferens","bool":false},{"option":"Prostatic cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Degeneration of epididymis","bool":false},{"option":"Obstruction of bulbourethral glands","bool":true}]},{"id":114,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"The prostate gland is which of the following types?","answers":[{"option":"Compound tubuloalveolar gland","bool":true},{"option":"Compound tubular gland","bool":false},{"option":"Simple straight tubular gland","bool":false},{"option":"Simple alveolar gland","bool":false},{"option":"Simple coiled tubular gland","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following congenital malformations most commonly causes recurrent abortions?","answers":[{"option":"Uterine agenesis","bool":false},{"option":"Unicornuate uterus","bool":true},{"option":"Mullerian duct fusion defects","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine synctium","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical incompetence","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Complete failure of the fusion of the Mullerian duct can result in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Septate uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical incompetence","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine didelphys","bool":true},{"option":"Unicornuate uterus","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following protects young women against heart disease?","answers":[{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":true},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following hormones is secreted by the placenta and is responsible for the maintenance of pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Progesterone","bool":true},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Pregnenolone","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following represents the stage in which the oocyte is surrounded by the single layer of cuboidal cells?","answers":[{"option":"Primary follicle","bool":true},{"option":"Primordial follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Graafian follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Mature follicle","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following represents the stage in which the follicle is arrested in the prophase-I of the first meiotic division?","answers":[{"option":"Primordial follicle","bool":true},{"option":"Primary follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Graffian follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Mature follicle","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following regions of the Fallopian tubes has the most numerous ciliated cells?","answers":[{"option":"Intramural segment","bool":false},{"option":"Body","bool":false},{"option":"Ampulla","bool":true},{"option":"Isthmus","bool":false},{"option":"Infundibulum","bool":false}]},{"id":122,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is a synthetic estrogen used in oral contraceptives?","answers":[{"option":"Norgestrol","bool":false},{"option":"Norethindrone","bool":false},{"option":"Estradiol","bool":false},{"option":"Clomiphene","bool":false},{"option":"Mestranol","bool":true}]},{"id":123,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is correct?","answers":[{"option":"Tamoxifen is used to treat infertility","bool":false},{"option":"Diethylstilbestrol increases fertility","bool":false},{"option":"Dexamethasone has weak inflammatory properties","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogens are mainly excreted in the urine unchanged","bool":false},{"option":"Tamoxifen is an estrogen antagonist","bool":true}]},{"id":124,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is related to twin-twin transfusion syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Dichorionic","bool":false},{"option":"Dichorionic and diamniotic","bool":false},{"option":"Monochorionic and monoamniotic","bool":false},{"option":"Monochorionic and diamniotic","bool":true},{"option":"Dichorionic and monoamniotic","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A fetus is born with an enlarged clitoris and fused labia majora/minora. Ultrasound confirms that the fetus is female. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"5-alpha reductase deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital adrenal hyperplasia","bool":true},{"option":"Turner syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Ovotesticular disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Mullerian dysgenesis","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Where are peg cells found?","answers":[{"option":"Ovary","bool":false},{"option":"Oviduct","bool":true},{"option":"Vagina","bool":false},{"option":"Cervix","bool":false},{"option":"Uterus","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which nerve provides innervation to the lower one-fifth of the vagina and receives touch and temperature sensations?","answers":[{"option":"Genitofemoral","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral","bool":false},{"option":"Pudendal","bool":true},{"option":"Perineal","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenal","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"How many carbons are there in androstenedione?","answers":[{"option":"20","bool":false},{"option":"14","bool":false},{"option":"19","bool":true},{"option":"25","bool":false},{"option":"17","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"What is the first hormone produced by the placenta?","answers":[{"option":"Luteinizing hormone (LH)","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":true},{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Progestin","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"A 30-year-old man comes to the outpatient department with pain in the anal region. Examination reveals abscesses on the anal glands above the pectinate line. The infection has eroded the lateral wall of the anal canal. Where is the infection most likely to spread after the anal canal?","answers":[{"option":"Levator ani muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Ischioanal fossa","bool":true},{"option":"Deep perineal space","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial perineal space","bool":false},{"option":"Tendinous arch","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2020","question":"Which of the following is produced by Leydig cells?","answers":[{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":true},{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone","bool":false}]}]
export default arr